Guide to the Jabez Lamar Monroe Curry Papers, 1854-1931
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Jabez Lamar Monroe Curry papers 1854-1931
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Curry, J.L.M. (Jabez Lamar Monroe), 1825-1903.
3.0 Linear Feet 736 Items
Statesman, author, clergyman, diplomat, and educator, of Richmond, Va.
Chiefly letters relating to Curry's career in education and diplomacy after the Civil War. Most of the letters were written by Curry to his son Manly Bowie Curry, giving him advice and discussing family matters and political and social questions. Includes two letter books covering the period of his envoyship to Spain and containing comments about Spanish customs and government. Also, a typewritten journal kept by M. B. Curry while serving with the United States Marine Corps in Nicaragua, 1930-1931.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Jabez Lamar Monroe Curry Papers were acquired by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library in 1941 and 1961.
Biographical Note
Statesman, author, clergyman, diplomat, and educator, of Richmond, Va.
Collection Overview
The major part of the collection is the correspondence of J. L. M. Curry with his son, Manly Bowie Curry, mainly in the years 1884-1903. The correspondence is personal, for the most part, but there are occasional references to Curry's career in education. The collection also contains two letter books covering a portion of the time Curry served as United States minister to Spain (1885-1888) which have extensive observations on Spain, its rulers, customs, and environment; a few items of correspondence with relatives; newspaper clippings; photographs of the Curry family and of the Philippines; and a typewritten journal kept by Manly Lamar Curry while serving with the United States Marine Corps in Nicaragua, 1930-1931.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Curry, Manly Bowie
United States -- Marine Corps -- Officers -- Diaries
Diplomats -- Correspondence
Fathers and sons
Diplomatic and consular service, American -- Spain
Nicaragua-- Politics and government -- 1909-1937
Spain -- Social life and customs -- 19th century
Related Material
Additional materials from J.L.M. Curry can be found in the correspondence series of the C.C. Clay Papers, also held at Duke.
Contents of Collection
- Papers, 1858-1931 and undated, (4 boxes)
  - Information folder (Box 1)
  - Letters, 1858-1899
  - Letters, 1900-1907 and undated (Box 2)
  - Clippings and printed materials
  - Pictures
  - Letterbooks, 1885-1887 (Box 3)
  - Genealogy
  - Miscellaneous and legal papers
  - Scrapbook, 1881 and 1903 (Box 4)
  - Manly Lamar Curry journal, 1930-1931